<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Apple Hot News</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/hotnews/</link>
<description>Hot News provided by Apple.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014, Apple Inc.</copyright>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 14:53:21 PDT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 14:53:21 PDT</lastBuildDate>
<category>Apple</category>
<generator>In house</generator>
<docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss/</docs><item>
<title>Apple Reports Third Quarter Results</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2014/07/22Apple-Reports-Third-Quarter-Results.html?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple today announced financial results for its fiscal 2014 third quarter ended June 28, 2014. The company posted quarterly revenue of $37.4 billion and quarterly net profit of $7.7 billion, or $1.28 per diluted share. These results compare to revenue of $35.3 billion and net profit of $6.9 billion, or $1.07 per diluted share, in the year-ago quarter. Gross margin was 39.4 percent compared to 36.9 percent in the year-ago quarter. International sales accounted for 59 percent of the quarter’s revenue. Apple’s board of directors has declared a cash dividend of $.47 per share of the company’s common stock. The dividend is payable on August 14, 2014, to shareholders of record as of the close of business on August 11, 2014. “Our record June quarter revenue was fueled by strong sales of iPhone and Mac and the continued growth of revenue from the Apple ecosystem, driving our highest EPS growth rate in seven quarters,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “We are incredibly excited about the upcoming releases of iOS 8 and OS X Yosemite, as well as other new products and services that we can’t wait to introduce.”</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 13:54:40 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Announces Eighth Annual iTunes Festival in London</title>
<link>http://www.itunesfestival.com</link>
<description>Apple today announced that Maroon 5, Pharrell Williams, Beck, Sam Smith, Blondie, Kylie, David Guetta, 5 Seconds of Summer, Calvin Harris, Chrissie Hynde, and many more of the world’s biggest artists will headline this year’s iTunes Festival. Returning to the UK for an eighth year, the festival will feature over 60 acts throughout September at the legendary Roundhouse. Performances can be watched live or on-demand on iPhone, iPad, iPod touch, in iTunes on a computer, or in HD with Apple TV. “The iTunes Festival in London is back with another stunning line-up of world class performers and tremendous new acts,” said Eddy Cue, Apple’s senior vice president of Internet Software and Services. “These live shows capture the heart and soul of iTunes and we love bringing them to our customers in the Roundhouse, as well as to the millions of people watching all over the world for free.”</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 11:20:06 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>“Alive Inside” Film Explores Power of Music to Restore Memory</title>
<link>http://recode.net/2014/07/19/alive-inside-film-documents-power-of-music-to-restore-memory-ipods-included/</link>
<description>Re/code writes about “Alive Inside,” a documentary that chronicles the experiences of Alzheimer’s patients who have been revitalized through music. The film follows social worker Dan Cohen, whose nonprofit works to bring iPods loaded with personalized playlists to elderly Alzheimer’s and dementia patients across the U.S. Re/code describes a scene from the movie where a 94-year-old dementia patient comes alive with joy as soon as he hears a song from his youth. “I had goosebumps over my whole body when he was waking up. I had tears in my eyes,” said filmmaker Michael Rossato-Bennett. “They say every artist only tells one story over and over again. If I had to tell my story, it’s the finding of life where you think there is none.”

</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 11:18:39 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sue Wagner Joins Apple’s Board of Directors</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2014/07/17Sue-Wagner-Joins-Apple-s-Board-of-Directors.html?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Susan L. Wagner, founding partner and director of BlackRock, has been elected to Apple’s board of directors. Bill Campbell, the board’s longest-serving member, is retiring after 17 years. Wagner co-founded BlackRock in 1988 and helped it become one of the world’s most successful asset-management companies. “Sue is a pioneer in the financial industry and we are excited to welcome her to Apple’s board of directors,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “We believe her strong experience, especially in M&amp;A and building a global business across both developed and emerging markets, will be extremely valuable as Apple continues to grow around the world.” Wagner has been recognized as one of Fortune Magazine’s 50 Most Powerful Women in Business and honored by the National Council for Research on Women. “I have always admired Apple for its innovative products and dynamic leadership team, and I’m honored to be joining their board,” Wagner said.</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 15:24:08 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple and IBM Forge Global Partnership to Transform Enterprise Mobility</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2014/07/15Apple-and-IBM-Forge-Global-Partnership-to-Transform-Enterprise-Mobility.html?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple and IBM have announced an exclusive partnership that teams the market-leading strengths of each company to transform enterprise mobility through a new class of business apps, bringing IBM’s big-data and analytics capabilities to iPhone and iPad. IBM MobileFirst for iOS will feature a new class of more than 100 industry-specific enterprise solutions including native iPhone and iPad apps; unique IBM cloud services optimized for iOS; new AppleCare service and support offerings tailored to the needs of the enterprise; and new packaged offerings from IBM for device activation, supply, and management. “iPhone and iPad are the best mobile devices in the world and have transformed the way people work with over 98 percent of the Fortune 500 and over 92 percent of the Global 500 using iOS devices in their business today,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “For the first time ever we’re putting IBM’s renowned big data analytics at iOS users’ fingertips, which opens up a large market opportunity for Apple. This is a radical step for enterprise and something that only Apple and IBM can deliver.”</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 14:24:51 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scripps TV Stations Deliver News in a Flash with Final Cut Pro X</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/final-cut-pro/in-action/scripps/?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Detroit’s largest broadcaster, WXYZ TV, is now using Final Cut Pro X, Motion 5, and Mac Pro to edit its news programs. And by doing so, it has significantly accelerated the time it takes to move a news story from field to air. Final Cut Pro X’s speed, ease of use, and high-quality output have impressed the station’s editors, and now parent company E.W. Scripps is rolling out the same workflow to its other 13 U.S. stations. “Final Cut Pro X and Motion 5 let us create stories faster than ever — and at a level of production quality unmatched by other newscasts,” said Ray Thurber, vice president of engineering at Scripps.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 11:23:41 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Announces Updates to iTunes U</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2014/06/30Apple-Announces-Updates-to-iTunes-U.html?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple has announced updates to iTunes U, bringing educators and students great new tools to build and experience educational content on iPad. Beginning July 8, teachers using the free iTunes U app can create, edit, and manage entire courses directly on iPad, and students will discover new ways to collaborate, including the ability to start class discussions and ask questions right from their iPad. “Education is at the core of Apple’s DNA and iTunes U is an incredibly valuable resource for teachers and students,” said Eddy Cue, Apple’s senior vice president of Internet Software and Services. “iTunes U features an amazing selection of academic materials for everyone around the world. Now, with the ability to better manage and discuss educational content, learning becomes even more personalized on iPad.”</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 11:34:42 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Brings Vibrant Colors and iSight Camera to Most Affordable iPod touch Model</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2014/06/26Apple-Brings-Vibrant-Colors-iSight-Camera-to-Most-Affordable-iPod-touch-Model.html?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple has announced that the 16GB iPod touch is now available in vibrant colors and equipped with a 5-megapixel iSight camera for just $199. The entire iPod touch lineup features the 5-megapixel iSight camera with 1080p HD video recording, 4-inch Retina display, Apple’s A5 chip, and FaceTime camera. iPod touch features an ultra-thin and light anodized aluminum design and is available in pink, yellow, blue, silver, space gray, and (PRODUCT)RED. iPod touch comes in a 16GB model for $199, 32GB for $249, and 64GB for $299, and is available in the US with worldwide availability in the coming days.</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 10:42:09 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Introduces New Entry Level 21.5-inch iMac</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/imac?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple today introduced a new 21.5-inch iMac starting at $1099, making the world’s leading all-in-one desktop even more affordable. It features a 1.4GHz dual-core Intel Core i5 processor, Intel HD Graphics 5000, 8GB of memory, and a 500GB hard drive. Configure-to-order options include a 1TB hard drive, a 1TB Fusion Drive, and up to 256GB flash storage. The new iMac is available through the Apple Online Store, Apple’s retail stores, and select Apple Authorized Resellers.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 10:59:03 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>iPad Air Helps Travel Writer Explore World Without Limits</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/your-verse/exploring-without-limits/?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Travel writer Chérie King has a passion for adventure. And when King — who was born with no hearing in both ears — sets off on an excursion, iPad Air is her constant companion. She has visited 31 countries and five continents, relying on iPad for everything from translations to maps to keeping up with flight changes. “iPad is one of my essential travel tools,” she says. Hoping to inspire other hearing-impaired people, King shares her adventures via her website and social media. “I’ve met countless deaf people, and they all tell me how brave I am for traveling,” she says. “But now that they’ve read my site, they realize they can do it too.”</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 09:17:46 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Esa-Pekka Salonen Orchestrates a New Sound With iPad Air</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/your-verse/orchestrating-sound/?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Renowned composer and conductor Esa-Pekka Salonen uses iPad Air to translate his ideas into orchestral scores and share his love of classical music with others. He constantly captures inspiration from the world around him and always has his device on hand to write bits and pieces of music. “iPad is the best tool I’ve seen to write down the first impulse,” Salonen says. He also uses iPad Air to compose, edit, and shape his pieces into full-length compositions, and calls it a partner in his creative process. Wanting to reach out new listeners, he developed The Orchestra app for iPad that provides an interactive, immersive look at all the elements of a symphony orchestra. “I created The Orchestra app to share my love of classical music,” Salonen says. “To make it more approachable, especially for the next generation.”</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 10:43:22 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Unveils iOS 8, the Biggest Release Since the Launch of the App Store</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/ios/ios8/?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple has unveiled iOS 8, the biggest release since the launch of the App Store, giving users new features and developers the tools to create amazing new apps. “iOS 8 offers simpler, faster, and more intuitive ways to use your device with incredible new features like iCloud Photo Library, a new Messages app, the QuickType keyboard, and an entirely new Health app,” said Craig Federighi, Apple’s senior vice president of Software Engineering. “We’re also giving developers amazing new tools to make managing your health and your home from your devices an integrated, simple, and secure experience.”</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 13:46:20 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Releases iOS 8 SDK With Over 4,000 New APIs</title>
<link>https://developer.apple.com/ios8/</link>
<description>Apple has released its iOS 8 SDK, the biggest developer release ever with more than 4,000 new APIs, giving developers the ability to create new apps like never before. “With more than 800 million iOS devices sold worldwide, the opportunity for developers is huge,” said Craig Federighi, Apple’s senior vice president of Software Engineering. “This is the biggest iOS release since the launch of the App Store. The iOS 8 SDK delivers more than 4,000 new APIs including amazing new frameworks, greater extensibility, and a revolutionary new programming language.”</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 13:44:10 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Announces OS X Yosemite</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/osx/preview/?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple has announced OS X Yosemite, a powerful new version of OS X redesigned and refined with a fresh, modern look, new apps, and new continuity features that make working across your Mac and iOS devices more fluid than ever. “Yosemite is the future of OS X with its incredible new design and amazing new apps, all engineered to work beautifully with iOS,” said Craig Federighi, Apple’s senior vice president of Software Engineering. “We engineer our platforms, services, and devices together, so we are able to create a seamless experience for our users across all our products that is unparalleled in the industry. It’s something only Apple can deliver.”</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 13:37:25 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple to Acquire Beats Music and Beats Electronics</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2014/05/28Apple-to-Acquire-Beats-Music-Beats-Electronics.html?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple announced it has agreed to acquire the critically acclaimed subscription streaming music service Beats Music, and Beats Electronics, which makes the popular Beats headphones, speakers, and audio software. As part of the acquisition, Beats co-founders Jimmy Iovine and Dr. Dre will join Apple. Apple is acquiring the two companies for a total of $3 billion, consisting of a purchase price of approximately $2.6 billion and approximately $400 million that will vest over time. “Music is such an important part of all of our lives and holds a special place within our hearts at Apple,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “That’s why we have kept investing in music and are bringing together these extraordinary teams so we can continue to create the most innovative music products and services in the world.” Iovine added, “I’ve always known in my heart that Beats belonged with Apple. The idea when we started the company was inspired by Apple’s unmatched ability to marry culture and technology. Apple’s deep commitment to music fans, artists, songwriters and the music industry is something special.”</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 13:59:26 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>NTT DOCOMO and Apple to Offer iPad in Japan Starting June 10</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2014/05/28NTT-DOCOMO-Apple-to-Offer-iPad-in-Japan-Starting-on-Tuesday-June-10.html?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>NTT DOCOMO and Apple have announced that iPad Air and iPad mini with Retina display will be available on the DOCOMO network beginning on Tuesday, June 10. “With the addition of iPad alongside iPhone, we now offer the complete lineup of Japan’s most popular mobile devices on the nation’s most reliable LTE network,” said Kaoru Kato, President and CEO of NTT DOCOMO, INC. Apple CEO Tim Cook added, “We are extremely happy for iPad to join iPhone on NTT DOCOMO’s network. The results on iPhone have been tremendous, and we look forward to delivering iPad to NTT DOCOMO customers.”</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 10:50:25 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Teachers Use iPad to Enhance Learning in Special Education Across the Globe</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/education/real-stories/special-education/?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>For special education teachers around the world, iPad opens up a world of possibilities. Meet teachers at three schools — Special School Poděbrady in the Czech Republic, the Awase Special Needs School in Okinawa Prefecture, Japan, and New York’s District 75, the world’s largest special education district — and discover how they use iPad and apps to motivate learning, improve social interactions, and encourage independence in the classroom and beyond.</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 14:08:49 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>2014 NHL Playoffs: Teams Turning to High-Tech Analysis During Games</title>
<link>http://nhl.si.com/2014/04/29/2014-nhl-playoffs-teams-turning-to-high-tech-analysis-during-games/</link>
<description>Sports Illustrated writes about how teams competing in the NHL’s Stanley Cup playoffs are using iPad to help. They’re analyzing video, visualizing trends, scouting opposing players, preparing for games, and more — all using apps for iPad. Coaching staff can pull out an iPad during a game and use its information to guide players in a way not possible before. “The ability to telestrate real-time on the iPad through the iBench app really allows us to not only show our players what is needed to succeed, but to teach our players how to succeed,” said L.A. Kings video coordinator Zach Ziegler.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 13:40:47 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Updates MacBook Air</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/macbook-air/?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple today updated the MacBook Air lineup with faster processors and lower prices. Now starting at $899, the ultra-thin notebooks feature powerful Intel Core i5 or Core i7 processors, fast flash storage, 802.11ac Wi-Fi, up to 12 hours of battery life, and Apple’s iLife and iWork apps. “With MacBook Air starting at $899, there’s no reason to settle for anything less than a Mac,” said Philip Schiller, Apple’s senior vice president of Worldwide Marketing. “Macs have never been more popular, and today we’ve boosted the performance and lowered the price of MacBook Air so even more people can experience the perfect everyday notebook.”</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 11:14:41 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Apple Reports Second-Quarter Results</title>
<link>http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2014/04/23Apple-Reports-Second-Quarter-Results.html?sr=hotnews.rss</link>
<description>Apple has announced financial results for its fiscal 2014 second quarter ended March 29, 2014. The company posted quarterly revenue of $45.6 billion and quarterly net profit of $10.2 billion, or $11.62 per diluted share. These results compare to revenue of $43.6 billion and net profit of $9.5 billion, or $10.09 per diluted share, in the year-ago quarter. Gross margin was 39.3 percent compared to 37.5 percent in the year-ago quarter. International sales accounted for 66 percent of the quarter’s revenue. “We’re very proud of our quarterly results, especially our strong iPhone sales and record revenue from services,” said Tim Cook, Apple’s CEO. “We’re eagerly looking forward to introducing more new products and services that only Apple could bring to market.”</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 14:12:18 PDT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>